Register of the Kenneth Rush Papers, 1937-1989
Hoover Institution Archives
Kenneth Rush Papers,
1937-1989
85019
Rush, Kenneth, 1910-
34 manuscript boxes (13.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches, memoranda, interview transcripts, financial records, and printed matter, relating to United States foreign relations with Germany and France, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, and United States foreign, economic, and defense policy during the administrations of Richard M. Nixon and Gerald R. Ford.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Dept. of State.; United States. Dept. of Defense.; United States--Foreign relations--Germany (West); United States--Foreign relations--France.; Germany (West)--Foreign relations--United States.; France--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--1969-1974.; United States--Foreign relations--1974-1977.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Economic policy.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Ford, Gerald R. (Gerald Rudolph), 1913-; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; France.; Germany.; Diplomats--United States.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
1910, Jan. 17 Born, Walla Walla, Washington
1930 B. A. degree, the University of Tennessee
1932 J. D. degree, Yale University
1936-1937 Assistant Professor, Duke University Law School
1966-1969 President, Union Carbide Corporation
1969 July-1972 Feb. U.S. Ambassador to the Federal German Republic
1972 Feb.-1973 Feb. Deputy Secretary of Defense
1973 Feb.-1974 May Deputy Secretary of State
1974 May-Oct. Counsellor to the President for Economic Policy
1974 Nov.-1977 Mar. U.S. Ambassador to France
1979-1984 Chairman, The Atlantic Council of the United States
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1942-1975 (Box 1)
  Correspondence, printed matter and reports arranged by form.
- UNION CARBIDE CORPORATION FILE, 1937-1969 (Box 1)
  Personnel questionnaires and speeches arranged by form.
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1939-1969 (Boxes 2-3)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically.
- OFFICE FILE, U.S. EMBASSY, GERMANY, JULY 1969-FEBRUARY 1972 (Boxes 4-8)
  Clippings and speeches and writings arranged by form.
- OFFICE FILE, DEPUTY SECRETARY OF DEFENSE, FEBRUARY 1972-FEBRUARY 1973 (Boxes 9-12)
  Speeches and writings, correspondence and schedule arranged by form.
- OFFICE FILE, DEPUTY SECRETARY OF STATE, FEBRUARY 1973-MAY 1974 (Boxes 13-15)
  Subject files and speeches and writings arranged by form.
- OFFICE FILE, COUNSELLOR TO THE PRESIDENT FOR ECONOMIC POLICY, MAY-OCTOBER 1974 (Boxes 16-17)
  Appointments, correspondence, speeches and writings arranged by form.
- OFFICE FILE, U. S. EMBASSY, FRANCE, NOVEMBER 1974-MARCH 1977 (Boxes 18-32)
  Personal file, correspondence and speeches and writings arranged by form.
- LATER YEARS, 1977-1989 (Boxes 33-34)
  Correspondence arranged by form.
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1942-1975
  - American National Red Cross (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biography (Folder 2)
  - Distinguished Civilian Service Awards Board (Folder 3)
  - Draft registration (Folder 4)
  - Institute of International Education (Folder 5)
- UNION CARBIDE CORPORATION, 1947-1969
  - President's letter, April 6, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Security questionnaires, 1947-1967 (Folder 7)
  - Speeches and writings. Typescript unless otherwise indicated
    - "'Research on Research' Needed by the Chemical Industry," Journal of Commerce, n.d. (Folder 8)
    - "Tooling Up For Effective Marketing," n.d.
    - Graduation address, Tusculum College, May 21, 1961
    - "The Operations of Union Carbide Corporation for the United States Atomic Energy Commission," November 2, 1961
    - "Education for a Life of Accelerating Change," December 15, 1962
    - "Let's Be Realistic About Exports and Foreign Investment," November 17, 1964
    - Address, annual meeting of stockholders, April 22, 1965
    - Comments, New York Society of Security Analysts, April 14, 1966
    - "Union Carbide's Current Progress Towards Attaining Its Long-Range Objectives," speech, Charleston, West Virginia, November 10, 1966
    - "Business Planning in Union Carbide," February 1, 1967. Also includes printed copy
    - Introductory comments, Underwriters' Information Meeting, February 16, 1967
    - "Communications and the Chemical Industry," American Business Press, March 1, 1967
    - Address, annual meeting of stockholders, April 18, 1967
    - Dedication talk, Hot Springs, Arkansas, May 20, 1967
    - Luncheon talk, Hot Springs, Arkansas, May 20, 1967
    - Address, Dinner of Governor Winthrop Rockefeller, Little Rock, Arkansas, August 30, 1967
    - Address, West Virginia Tech, October 14, 1967
    - "Reflections on Oak Ridge and Union Carbide Corporation," remarks at Oak Ridge Rotary Club Meeting, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, October 26, 1967
    - Address, annual meeting, April 18, 1968. Draft
    - "International Education and the Multinational Corporation," speech, Institute of International Education, October 15, 1968
    - Address, annual meeting, April 22, 1969
  - Travel (Folder 9)
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1939-1969
  - A-B (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Business Advisory Committee for Nixon-Agnew. Relates to the 1968 presidential campaign of Richard M. Nixon (Folder 2)
  - G-H (Folder 3)
  - J-L (Folder 4)
  - M-O (Folder 5)
  - P-R (Folder 6)
  - S-V (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - W-Z (Folder 2)
- OFFICE FILE, U.S. EMBASSY, GERMANY, JULY 1969-FEBRUARY 1972
  - Clippings
    - General
      - 1969 June 12-October 11 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1969 October 12-November 30 (Folder 2)
      - 1969 December 1-1970 January 30 (Folder 3)
      - 1970 January 31-February 5 (Folder 4)
      - 1970 February 6-April 13 (Folder 5)
      - 1970 April 15-June 30 (Folder 6)
      - 1970 July 1-October 21 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 1970 October 22-December 24 (Folder 2)
      - 1971 January 6-March 19 (Folder 3)
      - 1971 March 20-April 30 (Folder 4)
      - 1971 May 3-December 29 (Folder 5)
      - 1972 January (Folder 6)
      - 1972 February 1-9 (Folder 7)
    - Berlin Four Power Talks (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 1970 February 11-March 31 (Folder 2)
      - 1970 April 1-May 15 (Folder 2)
      - 1970 June 1-July 4 (Folder 3)
      - 1970 July 10-September 30 (Folder 4)
      - 1970 October 1-December 12 (Folder 5)
      - 1971 January 8-July 18 (Folder 6)
      - 1971 July 23-August 19 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 1971 August 20-24 (Folder 2)
      - 1971 August 25-31 (Folder 3)
      - 1971 September 3-4 (Folder 4)
      - 1971 September 5-28 (Folder 5)
      - 1971 October 1-1972 June 27 (Folder 6)
  - Letters on signing of the Berlin Four Power Talks Agreement, August, September 1971. Photocopies (Folder 7)
  - Speeches and writings. Typescript unless otherwise indicated
    - Untitled, n.d. Speech cards (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Remarks, October 10, 1969
    - Columbus Day dinner address, Berlin, October 12, 1969
    - "Which Countries Count in Europe?," Chiefs of Mission meeting address, November 11, 1969
    - "America: Guardian or Partner?," speech, Hessischer Kreis, February 20, 1970
    - "An Era of Negotiation - Its Objectives and Requirements," German Society for Foreign Policy address, March 10, 1970
    - "The American Security Interest in Germany," Farbstein Committee address, April 8, 1970
    - Remarks, inaugural ceremony, German-American Friendship Week, April 27, 1970. Draft
    - Remarks, principal officers' meeting, May 11, 1970. Talking points
    - Speech on Cambodia, May 12, 1970. Speech cards
    - Speech at dedication of new America House, Hannover, May 22, 1970. Speech cards
    - "The German-American Partnership: Its Necessity and Promise," German American Society address, Essen, May 25, 1970 (Folder 2)
    - "Ties Between Berlin and the Western World," American Chamber of Commerce address, Berlin, July 1, 1970
    - "The New Era in Europe and Its Meaning for America," read by Minister Russell Fessenden to the Foreign Policy Society of Munich for Ambassador Rush, October 20, 1970
    - "The Relationship of the European Communities with the United States of America," Europa-Haus Marienberg e.V., November 7, 1970
    - "America and Europe in the 1970s," German Atlantic Society address, November 25, 1970
    - "The New Era in Europe and its Meaning for America," The Department of State Bulletin, December 7, 1970
    - Speech before the Council of Foreign Relations, January 14, 1971
    - "The United States and Europe: The Continuing Need for Security," speech, American Club of Hamburg and the American Chamber of Commerce, Hamburg, March 17, 1971
    - "Dimensions of Partnership," Steuben Schurz Society address, Hannover, March 18, 1971
    - "An Agenda for the Alliance," Fuldaer Zeitung, Fulda, April 20, 1971
    - "Action in a Changing Environment," American Women's Club of Germany address, April 24, 1971
    - "Protectionism or Free Trade: A Decision for Our Time," Export Club of Munich address, May 3, 1971
    - "Protektionismus oder Freihandel: Wir mussen uns entscheiden," Export Club, Zeitschrift des Export-Clubs, Munich, June-July 1971
    - "American Diplomacy in Europe in a Period of Change," World Affairs Council address, Los Angeles, June 17, 1971
    - "Die Beziehungen der Vereingten Staaten zu den europaischen Gemeinschaften," Europa, Wunsch und Wirklichkeit, July 28, 1971
    - Speech on the signing of the Quadripartite Agreement, September 2, 1971
    - "The Berlin Agreement - An Assessment," speech Industrie-und Handelskammer zu Berlin, September 22, 1971. Includes transcript of question and answer period
    - Speech cards, October 21, 1971
    - "A New Role for the USA?", address at seminar on international affairs, September 27, 1971
    - "Berlin: The Four Power Agreement," Current Foreign Policy (Bureau of Public Affairs, Department of State) December, 1971
    - Remarks to U.S. Forces in Berlin, Tempelhof Airport, February 7, 1972
    - "The Berlin Agreement: An Assessment," January 20, 1972. Updated from the September 22, 1971 speech
    - "The American Commitment in Europe," January 26, 1972
    - Remarks, Golden Book Ceremony, Berlin, February 4, 1972
    - "The United States and an Expanded European Economic Community - Partners in a World Economy," speech, Rhein-Ruhr-Klub e.V., Duesseldorf, February 9, 1972
    - Speech material (Folder 3)
    - Speeches-Reactions (Folder 4)
  - Stamps, Commemorative (Folder 5)
  - Travel (Folder 6)
- OFFICE FILE, DEPUTY SECRETARY OF DEFENSE, FEBRUARY 1972-FEBRUARY 1973
  - Clippings
    - 1972 February-April (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1972 May-1973 February (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1974
    - A (Folder 3)
    - Allen, Peter, 1966-1974 (Folder 4)
    - B (Folder 5)
    - C (Folder 6)
    - D (Folder 7)
    - E (Folder 8)
    - F (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Ford, Gerald R. (Folder 2)
    - G (Folder 3)
    - H (Folder 4)
    - I (Folder 5)
    - J (Folder 6)
    - K (Folder 7)
    - Kissinger, Henry A. (Folder 8)
    - L (Folder 9)
    - M (Folder 10)
    - N (Folder 11)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Folder 12)
    - O (Folder 13)
    - P (Folder 14)
    - Q (Folder 15)
    - R (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - S (Folder 2)
    - Scheer, Dieter (Folder 3)
    - T (Folder 4)
    - U (Folder 5)
    - V (Folder 6)
    - W (Folder 7)
    - Y, Z (Folder 8)
  - Invitations
    - Accepted (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Regretted (Folder 2)
    - To the Secretary's residence (Folder 3)
  - Interviews (Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 5)
  - Nomination hearing before the Committee on Armed Services, United States Senate (Folder 6)
  - Schedules (Folder 7)
  - Speeches. Typescript unless otherwise indicated (Folder 8)
    - Addresses
      - Armed Forces Day Commemoration luncheon, Atlanta Chamber of Commerce, Atlanta, Georgia, May 15, 1972
      - National Security Industrial Association Cost Symposium, Washington, D.C., August 16, 1972
      - National Security Industrial Association, Washington, D.C., September 14, 1972
      - Department of Defense Procurement Conference, September 28, 1972
      - Army War College, Montgomery, Alabama, October 12, 1972
      - National War College, Fort Lesley J. McNair, Washington, D.C., December 4, 1972
      - Advisory Council, National Committee of Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve, Washington, D.C., December 8, 1972
    - Remarks
      - Governor's Conference, Washington, D.C., February 24, 1972
      - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, Rosslyn, Virginia, May 12, 1972. Two copies
      - Presentation of the National Transportation Award, Bolling Air Force Base, May 19, 1972
      - Reserve Forces Policy Board, Pentagon, May 25, 1972
      - Manufacturing Chemists' Association, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, June 8, 1972
      - American Council on Germany, Inc., New York, New York, June 19, 1972
      - Republican Candidates' Conference, Washington, D.C., July 1, 1972
      - Combined Federal Campaign, Pentagon, October 13, 1972
    - Statements
      - Ratification of the Seabed Arms Control Treaty, State Department, Washington, D.C., May 18, 1972
      - Pentagon press conference, June 23, 1972
    - Speech materials (Folder 9)
    - Travel (Folder 10)
- OFFICE FILE, DEPUTY SECRETARY OF STATE, FEBRUARY 1973-MAY 1974
  - Appointments and invitations, 1973-1974
    - Appointments book, 1974. Includes Kenneth Rush's positions as Deputy Secretary of State, Counsellor to the President for Economic Policy and Ambassador to France (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1973
      - Accepted (Folder 2)
      - Regretted (Folder 3)
      - Guest lists, Mrs. Rush (Folder 4)
    - 1974
      - January (Folder 5)
      - February (Folder 6)
      - March (Folder 7)
      - April (Folder 8)
      - May (Folder 9)
      - Guest lists (Folder 10)
      - Guest lists for functions hosted by Mr. and Mrs. Rush (Folder 11)
  - Board of the Foreign Service (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Casey, William J. (Folder 2)
  - Christmas gift thank yous (Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January 1973-May 1974 (Folder 5)
  - Departure (Folder 6)
  - Memoranda of conversations and reporting cables (Folder 7)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P. (Folder 8)
  - Personnel recommendations (Folder 9)
  - Procedures and miscellaneous (Folder 10)
  - Representation expenses and reimbursements (Folder 11)
  - Responsibilities (Folder 12)
  - Rhodesian chrome (Folder 13)
  - Schedules
    - Social, February 1973-June 1974 (Folder 14)
    - Social, Mrs. Rush, January 1973-May 1974 (Folder 15)
    - January-May 1974 (Folder 16)
    - Kissinger, Secretary Henry, March-April 1974 (Folder 17)
  - Speeches and writings. Typescript unless otherwise indicated
    - Foreign Service Day Message, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Parting remarks to Ambassador Ushiba, n.d.
    - Interview for German television, March 13, 1973
    - "The United States and the Changing World," remarks to Fulbright-Hays scholars honored by the Department of State and the Washington International Center, March 21, 1973. Printed copy in Department of State Bulletin, May 1973
    - "U.S. Policy Toward Eastern Europe," speech, U.S. Naval Academy 13th annual students' conference on foreign affairs, Annapolis, Maryland, April 4, 1973
    - "The Nixon Administration's Foreign Policy Objectives," Department of State Bulletin, April 23, 1973
    - Statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, May 2, 1973
    - Interview, United States Information Service, May 8, 1973
    - Statement before the Committee on Foreign Affairs, House of Representatives, May 15, 1973
    - "The NATO Alliance, the Basis for an Era of Negotiations," speech, Southern Council for International and Public Affairs, Atlanta, Georgia, May 22, 1973
    - Speech before the Industrial College of the Armed Forces, June 5, 1973
    - Statement before the Subcommittee on Foreign Commerce and Tourism, Senate Committee on Commerce, June 7, 1973
    - Statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee June 12, 1973
    - "The United States With Europe," Los Angeles World Affairs Council address, June 14, 1973
    - Speech to the Country Day School Headmasters' Association, Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania, June 21, 1973
    - Speech, workshop for foreign service families, Foreign Service Institute, June 22, 1973
    - "United States Troop Levels in Europe," testimony before the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Subcommittee on European Affairs. Printed copy with news release in pamphlet of Bureau of Public Affairs, Department of State, July 13, 1973. Appears as an article in Vital Speeches, August 1, 1973. Testimony before the Senate Subcommittee on Arms Control
    - Address to the SEATO Council meeting, September 28, 1973
    - Address, President's Conference on Export Expansion, October 11, 1973
    - Speech, Yale Law School, October 13, 1973?
    - Statement before the Senate Appropriations Subcommittee, November 5, 1973
    - "The Dilemma of Choice," United Synagogue of America address, November 13, 1973
    - Statement before the House Subcommittee on Foreign Operations, House Appropriations Committee, November 14, 1973
    - Remarks for Norwegian luncheon, November 27, 1973
    - "A New Era in U.S. - Latin American Relations," The Council of the Americas address, December 5, 1973
    - "The Middle East and Detente," Council on Foreign Relations, address December 12, 1973
    - Statement before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, December 13, 1973
    - Japanese Planning Group luncheon, December 18, 1973
    - "America and Asia: The Old and the New," Cleveland Council on Foreign Relations address, January 21, 1974
    - "U.S. Commitment to a Generation of Peace," commencement address, Tusculum College, Greenville, Tennessee, May 26, 1975
  - Speech material (Folder 2)
  - Travel (Folder 3)
- OFFICE FILE, COUNSELLOR TO THE PRESIDENT FOR ECONOMIC POLICY, MAY-OCTOBER 1974
  - Appointments, June-July 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Chronological, May 29-October 18, 1974 (Folder 2)
    - Congratulatory letters, May, June 1974 (Folder 3)
    - Personal (Folder 4)
  - Press conferences, press releases, interviews (Folder 5)
  - Resignation (Folder 6)
  - Schedules
    - 1974 June-October (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Rush, August-September 1974 (Folder 2)
  - Speech agencies (Folder 3)
  - Speeches. Typescript (Folder 4)
    - "Observations About Germany," n.d.
    - Speech, Tusculum College, n.d.
    - Remarks, National Association of Manufacturers, Washington, D.C., June 11, 1974
    - Address, July 26, 1974
  - Statements and testimony before Congress. Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Testimony, July 26, 1974. Draft
    - Statement, Joint Economic Committee, July 29, 1974. Also speech cards
    - Statement, Senate Committee on the Budget, August 14, 1974
    - Statement, Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs, n.d.
    - Executive privilege
  - White House
    - Camp David (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda (Folder 7)
    - Organizational procedure (Folder 8)
    - President Gerald R. Ford's remarks, August 9, 1974 (Folder 9)
    - Presidential yacht (Folder 10)
    - Telephone calls (Folder 11)
    - Travel voucher (Folder 12)
- OFFICE FILE, U.S. EMBASSY, FRANCE, NOVEMBER 1974-MARCH 1977
  - Personal file
    - Appointment, September 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Arrival in France (Folder 2)
    - Arts patronage (Folder 3)
    - Departure, March 14, 1977 (Folder 4)
    - Financial interests statements (Folder 5)
    - Hijacking of TWA flight 355 (Folder 6)
    - Interview about the Concorde airplane (Folder 7)
    - Monthly expenses (Folder 8)
    - Personal bills paid (Folder 9)
    - Resignation (Folder 10)
  - Appointments and invitations
    - Appointments book 1974 (Folder 11)
    - Appointments book 1975 (Folder 12)
    - Appointments book 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Invitations accepted and regretted (Folder 2)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Folder 4)
  - Commissary bills (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - A-B (Folder 6)
    - Abrasimov, Petr (Folder 7)
    - C (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Chambrun, Rene, comte de (Folder 3)
    - D-E (Folder 4-5)
    - F-L (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
    - M-S (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
    - T-Z (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Chronological file, October 10, 1974-April 4, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
  - Franco-American relations (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Guest lists, October 1974-March 1977 (Folder 2-7)
  - Miscellaneous information (Folder 8)
  - Office procedures (Folder 9)
  - Personnel
    - General (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Audit reports (Folder 2)
    - Evaluation reports (Folder 3-5)
  - Press corps (Folder 6)
  - Representation vouchers and allowances (Folder 7)
  - Replies to congratulatory letters (Folder 8)
  - Residence
    - Finances
      - Bills paid (Folder 9)
      - Expenses (Folder 10)
      - Monthly statements (Folder 11)
      - Petty cash (Folder 12)
    - Inventory (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Move to Paris (Folder 2)
    - Paintings (Folder 3)
    - Security (Folder 4)
    - Servants (Folder 5)
  - Schedules
    - 1974 November -December (Folder 6)
    - 1975 January (Folder 7)
    - 1975 February (Folder 8)
    - 1975 March (Folder 9)
    - 1975 April (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1975 May (Folder 2)
    - 1975 June (Folder 3)
    - 1975 July (Folder 4)
    - 1975 September (Folder 5)
    - 1975 October (Folder 6)
    - 1975 November (Folder 7)
    - 1975 December (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1976 January (Folder 2)
    - 1976 February (Folder 3)
    - 1976 March (Folder 4)
    - 1976 April (Folder 5)
    - 1976 May (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1976 June (Folder 2)
    - 1976 July (Folder 3)
    - 1976 September (Folder 4)
    - 1976 October (Folder 5)
    - 1976 November (Folder 6)
    - 1976 December (Folder 7)
    - 1977 January (Folder 8)
    - 1977 February (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 1977 March (Folder 2)
  - Social contacts
    - A-J (Folder 3)
    - K-Z (Folder 4)
  - Speeches. Typescript unless otherwise indicated
    - Remarks, presentation of credentials, Elysee Palace, November 21, 1974 (Folder 5)
    - Speech, American Club, November 25, 1974. Also a French translation and speech cards
    - Toast, Sons of the American Revolution, November 26, 1974
    - Remarks, France-United States Friendship Group, December 19, 1974. Speech cards
    - Speech on multinational cooperation, American Society of International Law, January 9, 1975 (Folder 6)
    - Speech, Anglo-American Press Club, January 31, 1975
    - Remarks, France-Amerique dinner, February 25, 1975 With French translation
    - Speech, Harvard-Yale-Princeton luncheon, February 28, 1975. With speech cards
    - Speech, Men's Club of the American Cathedral, March 12 (1975?). Speech cards
    - Speech, Association France-Etats-Unis, March 20, 1975. Speech cards and French translation
    - Speech, Diplomatic Press Association, March 24, 1975. With questions and answers following speech